Kevin J. Scelza

kevinscelza@gmail.com | (602)592-0808 | LinkedIn | GitHub

Professional Objective:

Full-Stack Web Developer with 4 years of experience designing websites using a responsive mobile first approach .My interests lean more towards the design aspect of development UI-UX.I am seeking a position that allows me to be part of a team that creates projects that are as functional as they are meaningful.I hope that any company that employs me will not only provide for their clients a product that exceeds their expectations, but also impacts the community they are utilized in, in an equally positive way.

Hard Skills:

Front-End: HTML5 | CSS3 | SCSS | Bootstrap | JavaScript | React | Redux | D3 | KeystoneJS | HandleBars |

Back-End: Node | Express | MongoDB | Mongoose | GraphQL | Helmet |

Testing: Mocha | Chai |

Graphic Design Software: InkScape | Gimp | Krita | SketchBook | ProCreate |

Related Technologies: Agile Methodologies | GitHub | G-Suites | Jira | Confluence | Slack |

Soft Skills:

Creativity | Problem Solving | Interpersonal Relations | Organization | Communication | Adaptability | Teamwork | Networking | Leadership | Time Management |

Work Experience:

June 2023 - Present

Software Developer/Banyan Labs-Remote

Phoenix, AZ

- Create UI design and layout of multiple web applications using Figma.
- Implement agile methodologies to dissect UI design into practical sprints and achievable tickets within Confluence and Jira

Apr 2021 - May 2023

Coding Instructor, Second Chance Center

Phoenix. AZ

• Teach HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap for an 8 week Front-End Workshop.

Military Service:

Dec 1983 - Dec 1989

U.S. Navy

• Operations Specialist / 3rd Class Petty Officer

Education | Certification:

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

Vocational Certificate or Credential, Computer and Information Sciences, General.Persevere Code Camp (full-stack), Tucson, AZ

Mar 1984 - Sep 1984

Vocational Certificate or Credential, Command & Control (C3, C4I) Systems and Operations.

US Navy Operation Specialist A School, Virginia Beach, VA

Sep 1979 - May 1983

High School Diploma or Equivalent, Liberal Arts and Sciences, General Studies and Humanities, Other.

Notre Dame HS, East Stroudsburg Pa., PA